Edward McMillan

Okemos, Michigan, United States

djmcmillan93@gmail.com

6789515143

linkedin.com/in/dj-mcmillan-56400028

Summary

Currently a full-time employee at Playmakers Athletic Footwear & Apparel. Worked in a variety of roles including:

- 11 years in teaching & coaching
- 7 years in management
- 5 years in web development

Utilized technologies & API's such as React, MongoDB, MySQL, GraphQL, Shopify-Plus, AWS, Pusher, Twilio, and many more to help drive eCommerce sales from less than \$0.5 mil/year to over \$15 mil/year over 3 years.

Experience

Web Developer

Playmakers Athletic Footwear and Apparel

Apr 2018 - Present (4 years 9 months +)

Drove Commerce growth from less than \$0.5 mil/year to over \$15 mil/year over 3 years

Significantly expedited Order Processing by creating an invoice auto-printing program with detailed order & product information for easy picking and shipping

Improved eCommerce product buildout speed through the utilization of multiple automation tools

Created a custom Queue Management to aid reducing wait times and provide an exceptional customer experience

Developed new Special Order system, which drastically reduced the number of errors and improved communication between all parties

Implemented dozens of custom-built applications that have allowed both online and in-store operations to scale efficiently and effectively.

Team Leader (Manager)

Playmakers Athletic Footwear and Apparel

Jun 2016 - Present (6 years 7 months +)

Utilized leadership and connection skills to develop staff and prepare them for successful careers, both at Playmakers and beyond

Clinic Outreach Coordinator and Instructor

Playmakers Athletic Footwear and Apparel

Jan 2015 - Present (8 years +)

Developed, coordinated, and taught hundreds of non-profit health & wellness-based outreach clinics

Good Form Running Clinic Instructor and Guest Advocate

Tortoise & Hare Sports

May 2014 - Jan 2015 (9 months)

Coordinate and schedule Good Form Running clinics both at the stores and at various events outside the store

Instructed Good Form Running Classes, creating a fun and informative environment where learning best thrives



🏊 Good Form Running Clinic Director

Big Peach Running Co.

Oct 2013 - May 2014 (8 months)

Recruited, trained, and developed Good Form Running Coaches to ensure that they provided the best possible experience for the students

Coordinated and scheduled Good Form Running clinics



🏊 Point of Sale System Coordinator

Big Peach Running Co.

Jul 2013 - May 2014 (11 months)

Effectively maintained the integrity of the entire point of sale system as to allow each store to operate as efficiently as possible and provide a seamless and enjoyable interaction with each guest

Accurately entered and received dozens of product orders each week, correctly including any applicable vendor discounts

Punctually added product SKU's and UPC's into the point of sale system, including product descriptions, categories, wholesale costs, retail costs, and margins

Assisted in the transition and implementation of the new point of sale system at each store, writing Excel VBA code to convert and consolidate SKU's

Guest Advocate

Big Peach Running Company

Sep 2012 - May 2014 (1 year 9 months)

Paralegal's Assistant

Law Offices of Gary M. Shapiro

May 2009 - Aug 2010 (1 year 4 months)

Worked with paralegal to increase productivity of the office by streamlining essential tasks

Created financial spreadsheet for the office to identify flow of assets

Helped conduct research to obtain crucial information on clients and defendants



🦚 Tent Manager

TNT Fireworks

May 2007 - Jul 2010 (3 years 3 months)

Conducted pre-operations analysis to estimate necessary workforce, resulting in maximum operational efficiency

Oversaw the financial aspects of everyday operation, minimizing unnecessary expenditures and maximizing profits

Kept precise financial books in order to accurately determine outflows, inflows and gross profits

Managed the general operations of the tent in order to most effectively capitalize from the sales, resulting in an increase in gross profit from 2009 to 2010 of 83%

Education

Michigan State University

Coding Bootcamp, Full Stack Development

May 2022 - Nov 2022

Gained desirable technical skills and invaluable industry knowledge to accelerate my journey into Development.

Georgia Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Science, Management; Pre-Law, Logistics, Materials, and Supply Chain Management

Aug 2007 - May 2012

BSM Concentration in Operations & Supply Chain Management.

Scholarship Athlete (Cross Country/Indoor & Outdoor Track).

Skills

GraphQL • MySQL • HTML • JavaScript • React.js • Node.js • Shopify Plus • MongoDB • Leadership • Analysis